Fred Rochlin papers, 1694-2002 (bulk 1880-1930),
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Fred Rochlin papers, 1694-2002 (bulk 1880-1930),
MS 401
Fred Rochlin.
1694-2002 (bulk 1880-1930). The Fred Rochlin Papers contain material relating to his research on the southwestern Jewish community. The collection includes material relevant to the history of Jewish individuals, commercial operations, and communal institutions in Arizona, principally southern Arizona.
63.75 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
Permission to reproduce, exhibit, or publish material from Series 7: Postcards must be obtained from Michael Rochlin (323) 661-2703.
Biographical Note
Fred Rochlin was born in 1923 in a house on a twenty-acre site three miles east of Nogales, on the Arizona-Sonora border. His parents, Annie (Shapiro) and Jake Rochlin, Russian Jewish immigrants settled in Nogales in 1917. Fred, the youngest of their five children, graduated from Nogales High School and briefly attended the University of Arizona, Tucson. In December, 1942, he enlisted in the U.S. Army Air Corps, and was stationed in Italy with 456th Bombardment Group. With 14 citations, he was the 5th most decorated flying officer from Arizona.
Fred enrolled in the University of California at Berkeley, and graduated with a Bachelor of Arts in Architecture in January 1949. While on campus, Fred met and married Harriet Shapiro, a UC Berkeley graduate in Hispanic America. They have four children and three grandchildren.
Following graduation in 1949, Rochlin apprenticed in the offices of two renowned architects: Frank Lloyd Wright and Charles Eames. In 1952, he partnered with Berkeley classmate, Ephraim Baran, to form Rochlin & Baran, Architects, Engineers and Planning. During his tenure as founding partner, 1952 to 1986, the firm completed major medical facilities and observatories in California, seventeen other states, and in Iran and Israel.
While professionally engaged, in his spare time he conducted a passionate search for data and images documenting the history of early Jews in the Southwest, with special emphasis on southern Arizona and Arizona-Sonora border. He was also active in historical societies: American Jewish Historical Society, board member; Los Angeles Historical Society, board member; Southern California Jewish Historical Society, president; Southern Arizona Jewish Historical Society, founding member, Pimeria Alta Historical Society, member.
Bibliography:
Books:
Harriet and Fred Rochlin. Pioneer Jews: A New Life in the Far West. (social history) Houghton Mifflin, Boston, 1984. 11 printings.
Articles, lectures, performances:
Harriet & Fred Rochlin."Tracking Leopold Ephraim," Western States Jewish Historical Quarterly, Vol. 1, No.2 January 1969, pp.75-84. Harriet and Fred Rochlin. (Introduction) "Reminiscences on an Arizona Pioneer."
Isaac Goldberg.Western States Jewish Historical Quarterly. April, 1970. Volume 2, Number 3. pp.172-181. Harriet and Fred Rochlin. "Marker 122: The Heart of Ambos Nogales,"
The Journal of Arizona History, Summer 1976) pp.161-181 Slide Presentation Fred Rochlin. "Jews of Santa Cruz" A 45-minute narrative on the pioneer Jews of Santa Cruz County, (Presented at the American Jewish Historical Society Conference, San Francisco, Ca.1998 and at the Harvard Club, New York City, 2000.
Monologue "Old Man in a Baseball Cap" 1:10-minute Monolog. Highways Performance Center, 1996 Santa Monica,; Actors Theatre of Louisville, Louisville, B Street Theatre, Sacramento, CA 1997; McDowell Colony, Petersborough, CT, 1998, Emelin Theatre, Manarroneck, NY, 1998, La Jolla Playhouse, La Jolla, CA, 1998,Taper Auditorium, LAPL, Los Angeles, CA, 1999, Northlight Theatre, Chicago, 1999; Coronet Theatre, Los Angeles, CA, 2001. et al.
Audio books:
Fred Rochlin: Old Man in a Baseball Cap: A Memoir of World War II. HarperCollins. 1999.
Fred Rochlin Old Man in a Baseball Cap: A Memoir of World War II. Harper Audio 1999 (Unabridged) 1999.
Organization
This Collection is organized into eight series. Five series contain subseries: Biographical Files, Research Files, Photograph Files, Postcards, and Ephemera.
Series 1: Biographical Files, 1942-2002
Subseries: Family, 1947-2001
Subseries: General, 1945-2001
Subseries: Military, 1942-2002
Subseries: Schedrin, 1952-2002
Series 2: Speech Files, 1972-1988
Series 3: Jewish History Compilation Notebooks, 1840-1999
Series 4: Research Files, 1694-2001 (bulk 1880-1930)
Subseries: Alaska, 1868-1961
Subseries: California, 1807-1986
Subseries: Colorado, 1980-1988
Subseries: General, 1882-2001
Subseries: Mexico, 1849-1960
Subseries: New Mexico, 1810-1996
Subseries: Photographic Research, 1868-1991
Subseries: Texas, 1813-1994
Subseries: Washington, 1858-1995
Subseries: West, 1800-1987
Series 5: Photograph Files, 1850-1986
Subseries: Borderlands, 1890-1970
Subseries: Copy Prints, 1850-1986
Subseries: Military, 1940-1986
Subseries: Miscellaneous Arizona and Southwest, 1870-1940
Subseries: Nogales, 1850-1970
Subseries: Western Jews, 1875-1950
Subseries: Exhibit Photographs, 1878-1929
Subseries: Oversize, 1868-1945
Subseries: Panoramas, 1916
Series 6: Oral Histories,
Series 7: Postcards, 1900-1985
Subseries: Michael Rochlin Postcard Collection 1900-1985
Subseries: General Postcards and Postmarks 1900-1930
Series 8: Ephemera, 1840-2001
Subseries: Arizona, 1880-1941
Subseries: California, 1873-1981
Subseries: General,
Subseries: Mexico, 1890-1910
Subseries: Military, 1940-2001
Subseries: Montana, 1880-1900
Subseries: Nevada,
Subseries: New Mexico, 1840-1937
Subseries: New York, 1840-1900
Subseries: South Dakota,
Subseries: Texas, 1858-1865
Subseries: Ledgers, 1866-1899
Scope and Content Note
Papers, 1694-2002 (bulk 1880-1930). The Fred Rochlin Papers contain material relating to his research on the southwestern Jewish community. The collection includes material relevant to the history of Jewish individuals, commercial operations, and communal institutions in Arizona, principally southern Arizona.
This collection primarily consists of autobiographical reminiscences, copies of historical records, correspondence, newspaper clippings, interview transcriptions and notes, photographs and postcards, and scholarly and popular articles and excerpts. The bulk of the material is photocopies of primary source material. Please note that dates listed reflect the subject content of the material.
Rochlin, Fred, 1923-2002 -- Archives; Rochlin, Fred, 1923-2002 -- Correspondence; Jews -- Arizona -- History; Jews -- Arizona -- History --Pictorial works; Jews -- Arizona -- Nogales -- History; Jews -- West (U.S) -- History; Jews -- West (U.S) -- History -- Pictorial works; Jews -- West (U.S.) -- Oral history; Jews -- Sonora (Mexico: State) -- History; Jews -- Belarus -- Shedrin; Pioneers -- West (U.S) -- History; Pioneers -- West (U.S) -- History -- Pictorial works; Nogales (Ariz) -- History; Nogales (Ariz) -- History -- Pictorial works; Mexican-American border region -- History; Mexican-American border region -- History -- Pictorial works; United States. Army. Air Corps -- Bombardment Groups, 456th -- History; Postcards -- Private collections; Jews -- Geneaology
Container List
- Series 1: Biographical Files, 1942-2002, 6.25 linear ft.
  Biographical Files is divided into four subseries. Subseries: Family (1950-2001) contains material regarding the personal lives, correspondence, and genealogies of Fred Rochlin and his immediate family. Subseries: General (1945-2002) contains correspondence with non-family, publications by the Rochlins, and high school reunion material. Subseries: Military (1942-2002) contains correspondence between Fred Rochlin and his family during his service in WWII, correspondence regarding the 456th Bomb Group, and official government documents relating to the service of Fred Rochlin. Subseries: Schedrin (1952-2002) contains personal correspondence and research material related to the Russian community of Schedrin, of particular interest to Fred Rochlin.
  - Subseries: Family, 1950-2001
    - Correspondence- Rochlin, Edith. 1990s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence- Rochlin, Jake. 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence- Shapiro, Sarah and Moise. 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Memorabilia- Articles. 1961-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Memorabilia- Marcus, Fred. 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Memorabilia- Photographs. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Memorabilia- Rochlin, Abe. 1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Memorabilia- Rochlin, Annie, Audio Tape. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Memorabilia- Rochlin, Edith. 1980-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Memorabilia, Rochlin, Fred. 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Memorabilia- Rochlin, Harriet. 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Memorabilia- Rochlin, Seth. 1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Memorabilia- Rochlin, Sidney. 1962-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Genealogy- Bereskin Family. 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Genealogy- Courtland Family. 1968-1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Genealogy- Merkin, Gladys. 1979-1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Genealogy- Levine Family. 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Genealogy- Nogales. 1977-1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Genealogy- Rochlin, Annie. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Genealogy- Rochlin and Shapiro Family. 1978-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Genealogy- Rochlin Family. 1985-2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Genealogy- Rochlin, Jake. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Genealogy- Rochlin, Sidney. 2001 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Genealogy- Shapiro Family. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Subseries: General, 1945-2002
    - Articles, About Rochlins. 1972-2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Articles, By Rochlins. 1980-1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Biographical Files. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence- Berkeley School of Architecture Reunion. 2001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Book Review. 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Braker- Capin. 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence- Edmonson, Monroe. 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence- Finney, Clyde. 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Morris, J.H., Jr. 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence- Morrison, Ray. 1964-2000 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence- Pozzo, Luigi and Vic. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence- Rochlin, Annie and Abe. 1945-2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence- Rosenbaum, Louis. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence- Russia Trip. 1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence- Udall, Morris. 1967 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Memorial Service, Rochlin, Fred. 2002 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Reunion, High School. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Reunion, High School. 1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Reunion, High School. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Reunion, High School. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Reunion, High School. 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Reunion, High School. 2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Subseries: Military, 1942-2002
    - 456th Bomb Group- Correspondence. 1962-1990s (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - 456th Bomb Group- Correspondence, Ostrom, Harry. 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 456th Bomb Group- Correspondence, Richtscheidt, Ed. 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 456th Bomb Group- Correspondence, White, Clayton. 1992-1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 456th Bomb Group- Correspondence, Whitmere, Lloyd. 1991-1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 456th Bomb Group- Microfilm. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 456th Bomb Group- Miscellaneous. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 456th Bomb Group- Reunions. 1991-1999 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Chronology. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence- Miscellaneous. 1942-1945 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Nogales Friends. 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - Correspondence, Katzman, Sam. 1944 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Letters Home. 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Smith, Charles. 2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Awards. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Enlistment and Discharge. 1942-1945 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Official. 1942-2002 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - Official. 1942-2002 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Subseries: Schedrin, 1952-2002
    Contains personal correspondence and research material related to the Russian community of Schedrin, Belarus, Fred's mother's birthplace and hometown.
    - Schedrin. (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
    - Belarus. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Blumkin, Rose. 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence. 1952-1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Goldberg Family. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Golutz, Eliezer. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Katz, Harry. 1987-1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Landslide, Schedriner. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Maps. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Morning Tag Journal. 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Parich and Other Towns. 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Rudin, Mickey. 1994 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Schedrin, Rodion. 1994 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Schedrin. 1964-1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Veterans of Soviet Army. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - White Russia. 1963 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Yitzkov, Bobruisk. 2002 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Series 2: Speech Files, 1972-1988, 1.75 linear ft.
  Speech Files (1972-1988) Speeches given by Fred Rochlin on the subject of his research into the Jewish Communities of the Southwest. Includes speeches, notes and related research material.
  - Fresno, C.S.P.P. 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ginsburg's. 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Los Angeles, Southern California Jewish Historical Society. 1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - New York City, American Jewish Historical Society. 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Nogales, Houle, Peter- Eulogy. 1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Nogales, Pimera Alta Historical Society. 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Nogales, Pimera Alta Historical Society. 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Nogales, Pimera Alta Historical Society. 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - Notes. 1982-1995 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Phoenix. 1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Phoenix, Temple Beth Israel. 1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - San Francisco, American Jewish Historical Conference. 1995 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Tucson. 1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Tucson. 1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Tucson, Temple Emanu- El. 1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tucson, University of Arizona. 1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Series 3: Jewish History Compilation Notebooks, 1840-1999, 1.25 linear ft.
  Jewish History Compilation Notebooks (1840-1999) include notebooks compiled by Fred Rochlin containing his personal notes and other material relating to the Jewish presence in Arizona from the earliest settlements in the mid 19th century to the late 20th century.
  - Santa Cruz County, Arizona. 1849-1999 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Western Jewish Place Names, Cattle Brands, and Officials. 1840-1960 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
  - Guide to References of Jewish Experience and Presence in Santa Cruz Co., Arizona. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series 4: Research Files, 1694-2001 (bulk 1880-1930), 25 linear ft.
  Research Files (1694-2001) contains eleven subseries. They contain newspaper clippings, census records, publications, interviews, articles, and biographical accounts of Jewish individuals, families, businesses and communities. They are divided by geographic area. Subseries: Alaska (1868-1961) Subseries: Arizona (1694-2001) Subseries: California (1807-1994) Subseries: Colorado (1980-1988) Subseries: General (1882-2001) Subseries: Mexico (1849-1989), Subseries: New Mexico (1810-1992), Subseries: Photographic Research (1868-1991), Subseries: Texas (1813-1994), Subseries: Washington (1858-1995), Subseries: West (1808-1987).
  - Subseries: Alaska, 1868-1961
    - Jews. 1868-1961 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Subseries: Arizona, 1694-2001
    - Aaron, Sam. 1866-1919 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Abraham, Sam. 1864 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Abrahams, D.B. 1889 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Abrahams Family. 1882-1952 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Atschul, Charles. 1882-1894 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Anti- Semitism. 1907 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Appel Family. 1859-1951 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Appel, Horace Hilary. 1862-1922 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Appel, N.B. 1828-1901 (Box 8, Folder 10-12)
    - Appel, Roy. 1971 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Arizona Territory Directory Listings. 1878-1907 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Backal, Alice. 1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Baer, Erwin. 1916 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Barth, Morris. 1885 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Barth, Sol. 1842-1928 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Bendell, Dr. Herman. 1843-1932 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Berk, Joe. 1928 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Berger, Jeannie Levy. 1892-1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Bernard Brothers. 1878-1907 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Bettwy Jr., A. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Bibliography, Notes. 1969-1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Bird, Mrs. A.T. 1926 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Bisbee, Arts and Humanities. 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Bisbee, History. 1870-1900 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Bisbee, Jews. 1890-1910 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Black, Mrs. Sarah M. 1882-1926 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Block, Benjamin. 1838-1905 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Bloom Family. 1869-1963 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - B'nai B'rith Grand Lodge #4. 1971 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Book Excerpts. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Bracker, Charles J. 1924-1967 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Bracker Family. 1886-1926 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Brooks, William E. 1874-1958 1874-1958 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Brown and Dickstein Families. 1911-1988 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Brown, Morris and Family. 1901-1987 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Brown- Wienberg Family. 1880-1933 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Business Listings. 1900 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Calisher Family. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Camp Stephen D. Little, Nogales. 1880-1961 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Capin Family. 1920-1995 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Census Excerpts. 1910 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Chanin, Abe. 1981-1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Chatham, Lillian. 1923-2001 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - City of Tucson Directory. 1881 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Clark, Mark. 1896-1913 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Clifton, AZ. ca. 1883 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Cohen, Charles. 1896 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Cohen, Jack. 1897-1973 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Cohn, Louis. 1888-1889 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Cohn, Max. 1870-1884 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Cohen, Dr. Morris Dobbs. 1880-1941 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Cohen, Sophie. 1971 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Coolidge, Dane. 1987 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Cummings, Peggy Titcomb. 1923-2001 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Czarnowski Family. 1848-1894 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Directory of Jews in Arizona Territory. 1880-1920 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Donau Family. 1866-1963 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Douglas, AZ. 1907 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Drachman Family. 1867-1937 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Drachman, Harry. 1869-1951 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Drachman, Mose. 1870-1935 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Drachman, Philip and Rosa. 1833-1889 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Drachman, Roy P. 1960 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Drachman, Sam. 1863-190511 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Dreyer, Sam. 1901-1903 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Duffield, Major Milton B. 1864 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Ehrenberg, Herman. 1820-1866 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Emanuel, Abraham Hyman. 1832-1915 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Ephraim, Gumprecht. 1896 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Ephraim, Leopold. 1850-1923 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Epstein, Lt. Fred and Fanny, 1869-1872 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Ezekiels Family. 1846-1972 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - The Fair Store. 1899-1965 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Farber, Manny. 1985 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Fein's Store. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Feldman Family. 1879 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Ferber, Rose Stein. 1890-1963 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Ferrin Family. 1870-1964 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Ferrin, Therese Mark. 1844-1927 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Fierman and Devere. 1889-1961 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Fish, Edward Nye. 1827-1914 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Fleischer Family. 1874-1908 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Fly, Camillus Sidney. 1849-1901 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Fleishman, Fred. 1857-1881 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Fortlouis, Albert. 1850-1905 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Frank, Abraham. 1867-1903 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Frank, Miss Lizzie. 1884-1919 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Frankenberg Family- Fair Store. 1872-1912 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Frankenberg- Newman Family. 1869-1972 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Franklin, A.M. 1857-1926 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Franklin, Mr. And Mrs. Selim. 1859-1929 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Franklin-Jacobs-Herring Family. 1814-1968 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Frenkel, Arthur. 1904 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Arizona, Research Files: Freudenthal Family. 1837-1975 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - From Oasis in the Desert to the Desert Caucus. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Ganz, Emil. 1838-1922 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Goldbaum, Abe. 1874-1902 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Goldbaum, Don Luis and Family. 1899 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Goldbum, Enrique. 1886-1904 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Goldbaum Family. 1865-1937 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Goldbaum, Hyman. 1896-1970 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Goldbaum, Julius. 1861-1927 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Goldbaum, Marcus and Family. 1833-1886 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Goldberg, Hyman. 1815-1889 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Goldberg, Isaac. 1836-1902 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Goldman, Charles. 1845-1901 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Goldschmidt, Adolf. 1878-1888 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Goldschmidt, Leo. 1860-1901 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Goldsmith, Alex. 1920-1929 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Goldree, Joseph. 1844-1897 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Goldwater, Barry and Family. 1860-1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Goldwater, Joe. 1830-1889 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Goldwater, Michael. 1821-1903 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Goldwater, Morris. 1852-1939 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Gotthelf, Isador. 1880-1931 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Greenwald, Lt. Sam. 1860-1900 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Hayden Collection. 1800-1865 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Hebrew Benevolent Society. 1884-1913 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Henderson, David. 1864-1892 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Herzog, M.T. 1876-1903 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Hishfeld, Herman. 1844-1902 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Home Missionary. 1886-1897 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Isaacson, Isaac. 1851-1926 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Isaacson, Jacob. 1853-1928 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Israel, Newton. 1868-1870 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Israel, Solomon. 1859-1931 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Jacobs, Agent. 1873 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Jacobs, Leon S. 1886-1923 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Jacobs, Lionel and Barron. 1841-1936 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Jaeger, I.F. 1797-1850 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Jerome. 1898-1984 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Jewish Businesses. 1880-1900 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Jewish Historical Society. 1981-1989 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Research Files: Arizona, Jewish Historical Society- Southern Arizona Chapter. (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Jewish History. (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Jewish Military Suppliers. 1865-1880 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Pioneers. 1860-1900 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Postmasters. 1864-1905 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Jewish References. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Religious and Cultural Development. 1870-1930 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Jewish Roots. 1854-1954 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Jewish Settlers. 1868-1918 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Women. 1854-1946 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Jews in Arizona. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Jews in Arizona. (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
    - Jews in Arizona, California, and Mexico. 1850-1900 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Jews in Arizona Research. (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
    - Jews of Early Arizona. 1853-1905 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Jund, Trixie. 1893-1981 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Katz, E.E. 1880 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Katz, Marcus. 1880 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Katzenstein Family. 1850-1940 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Kaufman, Albert. 1852-1931 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Kaufman Family. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Kaufman, Judah Aaron. 1874-1946 (Box 16, Folder 5)